# Ramanuj Mishra

■ mishra.ramanuj@gmail.com 🛘 647.832.2743 🕳 ramanujm.github.io/profile

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack developer with over 14+ years of experience in various areas of software development and IT technologies. Specialized Angular, AnJava, ular, Java, Spring Boot, Struts2, Hibernate, Spring MVC, Oracle. Enthusiastic, self-motivated, ability to work in a team, manage a group of people, manage projects and clients, develop and implement new software codes, cope well within a fast-paced setting, communicate effectively at all levels, and interact supportive within a team environment.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Dev lead – Full Stack Developer

Bank of Montreal (BMO)

Apr 2022 – Dec 2024

- · Developed Spring boot application and Restful web services API
- · Consume 3 rd party Restful web services API
- · Developed modular Angular application for web using Angular 10 later upgrade to Angular 14
- · Developed Ionic, Angular mobile app
- · Developed various HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript /Type script based UI component
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Implements AODA compliance for the application
- · Integrated 3 rd party Bio-catch library as part of biometric security
- · Creating Docker image using JFrog Artifactory
- · Configure and use Argo-CD 's Kubernetes to deploy the JFrog Artifactory docker image
- Utilized Postman API client to test Restful web services
- · Managed and support vendor services
- · Contributes to overall product development strategy and approach alongside other development leads
- · Communicate between Product Owner, scrum team member and Solution architect to track progress towards the goal
- · Managed several production release activities
- Help Production support team on Production deployment with 100% success rate.

· Developed various HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript /Type script based UI component

- · Participates in project review meetings to provide updates on progress
- Communicate to the vendor teams to ensure the seamless implementation.

# Dev lead - Full Stack Developer

• Developed modular Angular application for mobile and web

Bank of Montreal (BMO)

Mar 2021 – Apr 2022

- Integrated 3 rd party Acuant SDK in the application
- Integrated 3 rd party Bio-catch library as part of biometric security
- Developed various Restful web services API and Angular services to consume the services
- Creating Docker image using JFrog Artifactory
- · Configure and use Argo-CD 's Kubernetes to deploy the JFrog Artifactory docker image
- Utilized Postman API client to test Restful web services
- · Angular upgrade from 10 to Angular 14
- · Developed and performed Unit testing of the application
- Developed proof of concept
- · Participates in project review meetings to provide updates on progress
- · Coordinates with internal teams to ensure the seamless implementation
- · Contributes to overall product development strategy and approach alongside other development leads
- · Help Production support team on Production deployment with 100% success rate.
- · Communicate between Product Owner, scrum team member and Solution architect to track progress towards the goal
- · Managed several production release activities
- Provide technical help to team members and others.

# Senior Software Engineer – Full Stack Developer

#### MINISTRY O f CHILDREN, COMMUNITY AND SOCIAL SERVICES ( M CCSS)

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

- · Developed a Java Spring Boot and Angular based application
- · Developed various HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript /Type script based UI component
- · Use d SAML Security for Identity Provider to access the he portal and OAuth2 u th2 security to access REST APIs.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Develop ed various Restful web services API and different A ngular services to consume the services}$
- Developed Spring B oot micro services to communicate with different systems
- · Developed Single Page Applicat ion (SPA) system using Angular 8

- Implements AODA compliance for the application
- · Developed Localization and Internationalization using i18N of the A ngular application
- Utilize d Postman API clie nt to test Restful web services
- · Performed Unit testing of the application using J U nit and Angular unit testing using Jasmine and Karma
- · Use d Draw.io for prep aring application work flow
- · Prepare d technical design and documentation.
- Streamlined cross-team collaboration by integrating Agile methodologies and facilitating sprint planning sessions, leading to improved alignment and consistent delivery of project milestones.

### Senior Software Engineer – Full Stack Developer

B2B BANK Aug 2015 – Nov 2019

- · Developed a Java based Multi-threaded, Spring Boot and Angula r based mortgage application
- · Develop ed v arious RESTful API s and A ngular services consume RESTful web services
- Integrate and configure AWS S3 client and upload the document to the S3 bucket.
- · Use SOAP to send and receive data of the 3 rd party clients through IBM Integration BUS to integrate the system
- Developed data pulling from Expr ess to MOS using Quartz and MDB
- · Deve loped ASAP callback web module
- · Build Docker image and deploy using Jenkins CI/CD
- · Developed Single Page Application (SPA) system using Angular 6 and upgrade to Angular 7
- · Developed various HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript /Type script based UI component
- Use d 3 rd party Kendo UI Angular data grid to display data in grid form.
- Prepared various charts using 3 rd party Kendo UI Charts
- · Prepared application workflow using UML and Draw.io
- · Created technical design and documentation
- · Utilize d Postman API clie nt to test RESTful web services
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Performed Angular unit testing using Jasmine and Karma
- · Performed a pplication Unit testing using JUnit
- · Reviewed developed code s.

# Senior Software Engineer – Full Stack Developer

B2B BANK Aug 2017 – Jul 2019

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Developed multiple Spring B oot micro services and React Js component based application .
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Implement OAuth2 and JWT authentication for role base application.
- $\cdot$  Build Docker image and deploy using Jenkins CI/CD
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Developed vari ous HTML5, CSS3 and Type script based React UI component .
- Integrate 3 rd party Kendo UI and use Grid, chart, Date picker, and other features .
- · Created technical design and documentation
- · Utilized Postman API client to test RESTful web services
- Developed React Js component testing using cypress framework.
- · Performed application Unit testing using JUnit.

# Technical Lead – Full Stack Developer

ALTEN CALSOFTLABS Aug 2012 – May 20 15

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Developed a Java NIO, Multi-threaded, Spring 3.0 and Hibernate 4.0 based application
- $\cdot \ {\tt Designed\ an\ Ext\ JS/Tomcat/Oracle/Spring/Hiberna\ te\ based\ 3-tier\ web\ application}$
- Designed and developed system generated alarms collection for Time Pictra system
- · Develop ed custom drag and drop features using Ext JS API
- · Develop ed High availability mechanism using S pring, Hibernate and database triggers.

# Senior Java/J2EE Consultant

CAPGEMINI Apr 2011 – May 2012

- · Developed Pseudo code for various functionality
- · Participated in development of different module e.g.
- · Dyna Screen, Inbox, Auto Monitoring, Steps and Task module.

### **EDUCATION**

### Master's degree in Computer Science

2005

### **AWARDS & HONORS**

### Performance award

B2B Bank • 2017 - 2018

· B2B Bank Performance award.

#### **Initiative award**

B2B Bank • 2016 - 2017

• B2B Bank Initiative award.

### smart innovation award

BMO · 2023-24

· BMO smart innovation award.

#### **SKILLS**

Angular, Ionic, React Js, Jquery, Ext JS, Telerik Kendo

Object Oriented Analysis and Design (OOAD), J2EE Design Pattern

Java, XML, HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, Script, Typescript

RESTful, ESTful, SOAP

Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Web Services, Hibernate, Struts

Apache Tomcat, JBoss AS, Websphere AS

Intellij, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, RAD, Android Studio

Git Hub, Bit Bucket, Git Lab, SVN, MKS

Oracle, MS SQL, SQL Developer

Windows, Linux, macOS OS

Agile scrum, Test Driven Development (TDD)

Red Hat OpenShift, Ansible, JFrog Artifactory, Bamboo DevOps, Azure DevOps, Git Ops, Maven, JUnit, it, Postman, Swagger API, Karma, Jest, Selenium, Docker, Cypress, Kubernetes

Jira, Confluence, Kibana, Open Search, Adobe analytics, Dyna-trace, Threat matrix, Checkmarx, Veracode, SonarQube, Argo-CD

Freddy UI Framework, Splat UI Framework, JSON, RSA Security, PL/SQL, Java 11, Spring Security, OAuth2, Google tag management, Bio-catch, XML, LDAP, Spring cloud, SAML Authentication, AWS Nservice, service, Node.JS